The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
I've been waiting for you.
Ye Wuyou
First generation Suzaku
Ye Wuyou ?
What does Senior mean ?
Throughout generations, the successive Suzakus
were always appointed by the previous Suzaku.
The only way to inherit the legacy
is to obtain the Suzaku Seal
and seize control of the Cultivation Planet Crystal.
But if someone attempts to destroy the crystal,
then it will choose its own master
and make him the Suzaku.
And you
were chosen by the Cultivation Planet Crystal.
Why does he have the aura of the Suzaku Seal ?
That's...
the Suzaku's inheritance !
Impossible...
Impossible !
Without Zhuque Zi's approval,
how could he obtain the Suzaku's inheritance ?
Throughout 14 generations of Suzakus,
this is the first time the crystal has been destroyed.
So choosing him now
makes a lot of sense.
Are you willing to become the titled Suzaku ?
Will you be planet Suzaku's guardian
until the end of your lifespan ?
I'm not willing.
If you become the Suzaku,
you will be the supreme ruler of planet Suzaku
and worshipped by everyone.
The Heavenly Jade Sect
The Earth Soul Sect
The Immortal's Path Sect
pays respect to the Suzaku.
As Suzaku,
countless treasures will be yours.
There will be no obstacles in your cultivation.
If you leave now,
you will face countless dangers.
One misstep can lead to certain death.
If you stay and accept the Suzaku Seal,
you will rule the planet
and live a carefree life.
Why would you refuse ?
My path
won't stop at just planet Suzaku.
Very well.
To each their own,
I can't force you.
Senior,
how do I retrieve my soul strand ?
There are only two methods.
The first is to kill the spirit that holds your soul strand.
But finding your soul strand
among all those spirits
is unlikely
and cannot be forced.
The second method
is to trade
a life for a life.
You can go.
He actually rejected the Suzaku's inheritance ?
A life for a life ?
These two are my mortal enemies,
they're perfect to exchange for my soul strand.
But direct disciples of the Suzaku will be hard to kill.
I should make a distraction first
to weaken them.
The Cultivation Planet Crystal doesn't have a master.
Whoever obtains it
will rule planet Suzaku.
The Cultivation Planet Crystal !?
Rule planet Suzaku !?
This is a tremendous opportunity !
It's mine !
It must be mine !
Don't you dare compete with me !
Suzaku Formation,
activate !
The Cultivation Planet Crystal
belongs to me !
Give it to me !
Is he being possessed ?
Zhuque Zi...
Junior Brother,
this game was getting interesting
so I borrowed Qian Feng's lifespan to come here
and properly reunite with you.
Did you think that
I would give up planet Suzaku so easily ?
You possessed and consumed your disciple's lifespan
in order to replenish your own.
Senior Brother's methods are impressive.
Zhuque Zi !
This is bad !
Retreat !
This doll is made from celestial iron.
When you're in danger, activate its mechanism
and it will save your life.
If I had used it during a battle,
it would have killed me
before I killed anyone !
The time has come
to retrieve my soul strand.
That doll is made of celestial iron
and required centuries to refine.
Could it be that...
Zhuque Zi nurtured me from childhood
just to steal my body !?
That old bastard !
You're dead !
Transform !
The direct disciple of the Suzaku
is really hard to kill.
Seal !
Ceng Niu !
Why are you trying to kill me !?
I'm killing you
for my own sake
and because I promised Red Butterfly.
This is the end for you,
accept your death.
Have you forgotten
the Ancient God Blood Sword ?
Ancient God Blood Sword
This is...
Ancient God blood ?
My Qian Family's ancestors once said...
that this sword can only be unsheathed if the family is in danger.
Ceng Niu...
Since it has come to this,
you can rest in peace now !
Die !
The blood on this sword
is the true blood of a 9-star Ancient God !
How could Qian Feng have this as his last resort ?
Killing him
will not be easy.
Tuo Sen !
What is this monster ?
Die !
So the puppet was just a decoy
and his Divine Sense was in the monkey.
I didn’t want to resort to using this method
because it will slightly damage my Divine Sense.
But that puppet
was utterly worthless.
But now, with a drop of Ancient God blood,
the Cultivation Planet Crystal is mine !
After thousands of years...
I will
finally break free !
Little brat,
wait until I obtain the Cultivation Planet Crystal
and then I'll come to deal with you.
If Tuo Sen is back,
then I can’t stay here.
I use Qian Feng’s life
to reclaim my soul strand !
Red
Butterfly...
Trade !
Qian Feng, oh Qian Feng...
When you used me as your cultivation furnace
did you ever imagine this day ?
Reverse !
Brother Wang...
Senior Yunque taught her the furnace reversal technique.
By killing Qian Feng,
you gave Zi Xin
his Soul Transformation cultivation.
The Suzaku Tomb's collapse is so bad that
even Situ Nan’s teleportation jade slip is struggling to activate.
Wang Lin...
Now it’s your turn.
You do have some skill.
It's no wonder that a mere Core Formation brat
was able to obtain the memory inheritance.
Merge !
It's a pity that
you can’t stop me.
Come back here.
Come out !
Explode !
What
is happening ?
If I make it out alive,
I need to refill the Soul Flag.
Even Zhuque Zi and I weren't able to stop him.
But Wang Lin somehow killed him alone.
The Cultivation Planet Crystal...
Where is the Cultivation Planet Crystal !?
To think that you could do this...
Wang Lin...
I really underestimated you.
The self-detonation of all the souls in the Billion-Soul Flag
wasn't enough to destroy a sliver of his Divine Sense.
Die !
I don't think that the Heaven Defying Bead
can even help me escape from Tuo Sen.
Seal.
This farce
ends here.
Who are you ?
It doesn't even matter who you are.
Once I break free,
I will kill you !
You...
You are...
Zhuque Zi,
will you admit your mistake ?
Junior was wrong.
I beg Lord Envoy for forgiveness.
Envoy ?
The Envoy of the Cultivation Alliance !
Zhuque Zi,
you dared to destroy the Cultivation Planet Crystal
which is unforgivable.
But given the circumstances,
the Cultivation Alliance will let it slide.
You can leave now.
Junior Brother...
In the end,
you still
weren't able to defeat me.
I...
Senior Brother...
None of us won.
We both lost miserably.
This person
feels strangely familiar.
So...
Does Brother Ceng Niu
not recognize me ?
It's you !
Even if it looks like the Billion-Soul Flag exploded here, it didn't. Wang Lin even mentions the need to refill it later.
What happened in the novel is that Wang Lin took out all of the souls inside the flag to make them self destruct in hope of killing Tuo Sen's Divine Sense but he was also fighting with Zi Xin at the same time with a few primary souls. Those souls survived and returned to the Billion-Soul Flag after the fight.
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.